You hacked seven out of 16 publicly
launched companies of the Y Combinator
spring batch in 30 minutes.
>> In our batch, over 95% of companies said
that they were using AI to help with
their coding. However, on the note of
security, a small team developing
software just could not build as quickly
as mission-critical of a software that
requires such attention to security. And
that's just not true anymore. So, out of
these 16 companies, they were in
different life cycles of their stage.
But then they add a new feature through
just live coding, and that ultimately
caused a new vulnerability into your
system. The first prototype of Kiro, I
basically developed a specification
around how should this website look like
I'm building, and then I basically just
let it run, and I went for lunch. When I
came back, I was horrified. It was I had
actually never had access to my AWS
credentials. But wait, it's online. So,
now we live in a world where we're
writing exponentially more code, while
the security posture of them have not
improved. And so, that compelled me to
start Kastro.
[Music]
Before we jump into this episode, I
wanted to let you know that this podcast
is for developers building with AI at
the core. So, whether that's exploring
the latest tools, the workflows, or the
best practices, this podcast is for you.
A really quick ask, 90% of people who
are listening to this haven't yet
subscribed. So, if this content has
helped you build smarter, hit that
subscribe button and maybe a like. Back
to the episode.
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the AI Native Dev. We are going to have
a very fun episode, a very lively
episode, I'm sure this time around. We
have Renee Brandel, who is the
co-founder and CEO of Kastro. And let me
give you a few highlights before we
introduce Renee and and and kick into
this episode. Renee was previously the
head of product at AWS and the inventor
of Kiro. So, he is very knowledgeable
and deep into the into the spec-oriented
world. So, we're going to have some
great topics of conversation there. Um
after that, Renee went ahead and founded
a company called Kastro. And Kastro's
mission is to make all software
effortlessly secure. Wonderful mission.
One of the most amazing stats from this
is And of course, actually, Renee is
going to be giving an episode at the AI
Native Dev Con, which we'll talk about
in just a sec. But one of the beautiful
stats from this is Renee hacked seven of
16 YC publicly launched companies of the
Y Combinator spring batch in, get this,
30 minutes. And as Renee said, this gets
him into most conferences just alone
from that from that quote. We We're
going to talk about that and a bunch
more. But without further ado, Renee,
welcome to the episode. How are you? I'm
good. Super happy to be here. Thanks for
having me.
Absolutely, it's an absolute pleasure.
So, so Renee, you are the co-founder and
CEO of Kastro. Give us a very brief
introduction
to yourself and also what you do as part
of this role.
Yeah, absolutely. So, as you mentioned,
I'm I'm now startup founder.
Our company performs autonomous security
testing against AI apps and agents. And
so, think about it like as if you have a
pen tester on steroids that can really
pen test thousands of different attacks
at the same time and tell you which
vulnerabilities your software has, so
then you can just fix the ones that are
truly exploitable.
Awesome. Awesome. And
you know, before we jump into into
Kastro and some of those amazing things
in the security space, you've done some
pretty pretty cool stuff at some pretty
you know, previous companies.
Skype, Microsoft, AWS, couple of small
startups there.
What are the common learnings would you
say through those experiences that that
that you can teach us about? Yeah, so I
think the most important piece that I've
taken away from all of these different
experiences really focused on the
customer experience. I think it's very
easy to to kind of get bogged down into
one particular metric, one particular
issue, right? But always looking at the
overarching customer experience and
continuously optimizing for that always
pays for the long-term dividends. Right?
Um
I I started my I think my first uh my
first like software engineering job was
at a
database RM company called Prisma. It
was my first time actually learning how
to focus on developer experience, why it
really matters. Every single keystroke
of what a developer is typing truly
needs to help them get their job done
faster, and that ultimately started
building more and more developer tools.
So, at Skype, I worked on the Skype web
SDK, like a little chat widget you can
embed everywhere. And back then, there
was like a phase in I think 2015, 2016
where chatbots were cool, but it was
really nowhere as useful as it today,
right? And And then ultimately, yeah, at
Microsoft, I helped also develop
um a web SDK that connects with that
connects with voice recognition and
actually allows you to talk to
assistants like Cortana at the time. Um
yeah, and my last job at AWS, I was
working on Kiro. I I invented it. It was
one of the most fun projects because we
were really trying to figure out how can
we build entirely new developer
interface almost um using a
specification and what kind of
opportunities could that unlock. And
also kind of striking the balance
between like what's practical right now
versus where we see the future going and
how we can pay these exponentially
um pay back these exponentially
improving dividends, right?
Yeah, yeah. Wow, so many questions. I'd
love to go through with with with some
of that.
Before we jump into Kiro, and I'd love
to I'd I really enjoy what you kind of
like said there about the today and the
tomorrow and what's what's possible. I'd
love to dig into that. Um there's one
other thing that that is kind of like a
claim to fame, which is um you won
Europe's largest hackathon back in 2016,
which seems crazy. Like, oh my god,
that's a decade ago, right? But But it
was a you built a voice-to-code agent.
And this was obviously, you know, when
did When When When was the big boom of
of of ChatGPT and things like that? Back
in 2022, was it? Like I can't remember.
2023, I think. Yeah, somewhere around
that region. 2022, 2023. Um So, so this
was before GenAI was was a big thing on
everyone's lips. And you know, most
C-levels weren't, you know, encouraging,
let's say, that their their companies to
to find to to to wedge and shoehorn AI
into everything they do.
So, I guess, you know, from that point
of view, did that did that kind of like
really help your your growth in the in
the LLM AI space, your your way of
thinking?
Talk us through a little bit about that.
Yeah, yeah. I mean,
as you said, it was almost a
a decade ago. Now I kind of feel very
old now that you mentioned it.
Um but yeah, the the the technology
landscape at that time was completely
different. Like when you want to build
anything with AI, it wasn't as
as random access, as free form as you
have today with generative AI. So, for
example, when we wanted to build this
voice-to-code agent,
uh you have to start off with this few
like preset kind of routes that existed.
So, like at the beginning, you could
talk to it and be like, "Hey, I want to
build a blog post web app or a
e-commerce site and whatnot." And then
we would use intent recognition that
effectively realized, "Oh yeah, you want
to build something." And then entity
extraction, is it like a website, a
mobile app, is it a blog, is it an
e-commerce site and whatnot. So, you
have to actually programmatically
include a lot of these different flows
in your thinking, and then extract out
and map that ultimately to programmatic
code, right? Like very deterministic
code.
And it was really cool. It was an
amazing demo. But obviously, because you
have to kind of follow a this
quasi-fixed routes, if you will, um it
wasn't does not give you like the the
utility as you would have today with
most coding agents, right? Because with
coding agents, there you have just so
much free form access. Like you can just
look up this file that's somewhere on my
machine, and then take that information,
combine it with this. Like this is
impossible to have done it back then.
And even back then, technologies that
was totally different. We had to use IBM
Watson,
Google Cloud, and Microsoft Language
Understanding Service.
Now it's called Now it's obviously an
Azure service. Just like wire all these
things together. It's much harder to
build. Um
but it was a it was a time where I I
almost felt like, you know, I opened the
door to the future and could kind of
glimpse through of what kind of what
what opportunities will exist as
technologies become better.
And And yeah, I mean, this was before
most of my most of my technical career
as as engineering manager as a software
engineer and a product manager.
And it really also made me fall in love
with this concept of
working with developers and focusing on
developer experience because there's so
much you unlock in this. You can really
create a world where you can speak
anything into existence. And I think
that's so unique about software
development. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. And And there's a there's a
few things there that are that are super
interesting. Um almost like technology
jumps that really unlock the potential
for things like
AWS Kiro, right? Um whereby, you know,
every product that tries to, you know,
change the way or rethink the way things
are done, they they need certain things
to be in place. Timing is absolutely
key. Not just technology, but but
individuals, developers, and users to to
be able to consume that. And I think
obviously with the
with the with the leap that we've seen
with LLM's and and and agents in
particular being able to
being able to take on tasks without the
user being as prescriptive with the with
with their requirements.
Um
When we think about things like spec
driven development, um how
First of all,
you know, when we when you mentioned
before about the what's possible today
versus, you know, what's more of a
future kind of thing. Where do you think
spec driven development and maybe that's
a quite an overloaded term these days,
but how how possible do you think spec
driven development is today? What parts
can we really leverage today versus we
should be exploring these types of
things, but ultimately it's something
that we need to look forward to as a
future vision.
Yeah, yeah. I think with spec driven
development today, we see
a lot of even our own team in Kaskada,
we see a lot of good value for you to
create like
individual features at extremely high
quality, right? Cuz if you if you've
ever done a lot of live coding, you
know, it's like it feels like a video
game. You go back and forth and trying
to always like make a little bit of
incremental progress, but you actually
it's hard for you to see the entire map,
if you will, of how you're supposed to
land at a particular
particular outcome.
With spec driven development, what I
like is that you've done a lot of the
thinking up front. Like you think about
like what are the use cases? What are
the customer experiences you actually
want to unlock? What are the constraints
in the system? How should you be working
against those constraints? You actually
iterate on the spec quite a bit, right?
And then you one shot a lot of code. And
so I think it is really good for you to
have boundaries in the features you're
building and then deeply, deeply
internalize what are the end customer
experiences you want to unlock, work on
getting to the right level of fidelity
there as deep as you can and then from
there generate code. And that that's
just been a huge unlock.
For example, for for us, you know, we're
building a AI agent that actually hacks
other software, right? So with every
single
every single like vulnerability that we
find, we create a gym, if you will, that
the agent trains against. And we can
just write a specification of like a
base gym of what are all the different
constraints, how's it deployed, is it,
you know, does this one have to be
deployed in a Kubernetes cluster? This
can this just be a serverless app? Um
And then and then this this stencil, if
you will, of a spec gives us a lot of
the constraints in the system out of the
box without being too rigid in terms of
like how it's programmatically
implemented.
And then we can write specific
requirements for each individual
vulnerability that we find. And so that
allows us to be super, super quick in
developing these new new uh gyms and we
can just develop, you know, hundreds of
them a day. And with, you know, the
better just like in real life, if you go
to a gym more, if you do consistently
over time, you get you get obviously
better over time, too. Yeah.
Yeah. And these gyms, would you say
they're like how how specific are they
or or or general are they to to
industries, organizations? Would should
we should we look be looking at building
our own gyms or are these gyms kind of
shareable?
Yeah, yeah. So I think
um I think right now the way to think
about what's practically the the
landscape in spec driven development is
I would treat gym as a feature from
Kaskada and you can build like really
good features using specifications. Like
can be very unique.
I I think that is the world we live in
today, but we are moving to a new world,
I think. So what I'm seeing is
a lot of teams that are small and high
density in talent can outperform many
larger organizations.
And I think that's always been true of
like some breakout startups that I see
it now like more than ever.
And the best way to outcompete larger
teams is to shift our mindset from
building individual features
to figuring out how do we build
individual reinforcement loops that just
make the feature better over time.
And so a example is
when when our agent
actually performs a penetration test and
tries to exploit a system and realizes,
"Hey, there is this thing there that I
have a hunch on, but I don't have the
right tools to actually try to make that
exploit attempt."
It is actually going to go kick off a
new coding agent that now realizes, "Oh,
wait, there is this tool gap that I
have. Let me go quickly build a new tool
and then include it in the next
deployment. So next time a new customer
comes around and we're doing new tests,
now the agent has more capabilities."
It's almost like you need to think about
how do you use your own agent to
self-improve the product every single
day.
And that way a small team of individual
developers can outcompete entire
engineering organizations because as you
sleep, the product just gets better,
right? And that is that's a mindset
shift that will have to happen. And I
think a lot of opportunities are still
there. Like should this be a development
framework that needs to exist around
this? Like right now we handle all of
that ourselves and yeah, I I just think
that's a that's a new paradigm we'll see
in the next couple of years. Yeah, and
and it's a really interesting and
important area that is probably not
thought about as much when we think
about the improvements. People are
thinking more about the improvements to
the app versus their workflow, how
things get built versus what is getting
built, which is an important distinction
to make. Yeah, yeah. Absolutely.
Now now you mentioned live coding as
well alongside
alongside kind of like a more spec
driven approach.
Do you see spec driven as something that
is replacing live coding or do you feel
like there are, you know, they each have
a a role, each have a task and you use
them in different for different for
different reasons?
Yeah, I I firmly believe that both will
exist in for their own use cases. And I
will even go further. I think hand
authoring code will also exist.
Like you know, we will not
we will not be, you know,
looking back in time and be like, "Oh
yeah, we should only do spec driven
development or should only do live
coding." I think what we will realize is
that um
these new paradigms
have introduced new ways of how
developers can stay in the flow.
And when you stay in the flow, it means
you need to achieve your outcome in a
very like
like productive manner that's peaceful
where you're just like working towards
when you're locked in, you know? Um and
and I think when you do like for example
very specific hand author code changes
these days, it's because you have your
brain has been thinking about an
algorithmic problem and you're really
going to tease apart like what is
exactly going on here that I need to
just manually modify to get this
unprecedented optimization out. Right?
And I think with live coding, what we'll
see is
right now it is it is just like people
use it obviously for for production code
and whatnot, but I think what we'll see
is that it is becoming the best way to
quickly prototype new ideas and try
things out. Like the the idea of like,
"Okay, seeing things live, things are
iterating fast and then you have, you
know, you're you're make a change that
you want to immediately prototype out.
You want to ship it to your customer to
see before you really like pour in the
cement, if you will, right? To like lock
that feature in, you can quickly
experiment." If you look at most um
most Y Combinator startups, they have
built companies worth of code before
actually settling down on an idea.
Because now you can just experiment so
much faster, right? I've actually seen
some companies that live live code new
features while they're doing a demo to
the customer because they're like, "Hey,
is this what you're looking for? You
know, this is like this is something we
can build in, can come down the road
map" and kind of just create new
opportunities on the fly. And so I think
that's what live coding is really,
really good at. It even allows the the
customer to almost be able to say,
"Look, let me tell you what I'm looking
for." And they could even they could
almost like live code a solution as well
to say, "What about this?" And
I was talking with someone who was um
um they they were a developer
or rather they were leading a
development team and it was their design
team that kind of came to them and said,
"Hey, do you know what? I think I'm the
bottom neck now." And so they set them
up with Cursor and I can't remember what
else, but they then were able to live
code various things to get, you know,
various design works or design artifacts
built in a way that engineering teams
and others could kind of more gracefully
see what they're trying to show and and
you know, you can get a much nicer POC
or at least prototype of of that kind of
thing. It's amazing what it unlocks. It
raises the floor to
of like what software is. Like there's
at least a very base minimum that's very
good already that people can obviously
start off on. Like we actually see that
in our own team because we are a
security company, obviously. And so we
have security engineers, security
experts, right? They have used Python
their entire life because it's really
good to build out scripts to show
different exploits and whatnot. Um but
when they see a gap in our product,
which is almost all TypeScript, they can
actually start creating prototypes of
what they would like to have changed and
then show our engineering team and then
we can then take it forward on the
engineering side to really like um
productionize the environment. So, it is
this it's it's not only just the
ability for uh
for people to enter the space easily,
but also I think it unlocks a new way of
how engineers work with other
cross-functional roles, right? Because
now they're kind of brought together
when it's we're speaking the same
language now. Like this this can work.
Yeah. So, so you talk about raising the
the the floor, which I love that analogy
because it kind of really shows us that
well, it's not, you know, vibe coding
isn't just for engineers, but it allows
others to be able to enter software
development certainly at a POC or a a
prototype level. And I guess when we
think about raising the ceiling, this is
where spec-driven development or the
ability to to to write more write using
natural language more concisely to to
describe what we want and have that
built in a more predictable way. And
that's, you know, not just for
engineers, but I think one of the things
that engineers are lacking from vibe
coding. And and it's not just that
detail in a in a spec, but the ability
to
trust the output of that through
validation and so forth. I'd love to ask
you some some questions about, you know,
obviously you were there at
from day zero at Kiro. First of all, I'd
love to ask you what, you know, what
makes a good spec? And I'd love to talk
about this more first of all from a a
general perspective, but leaning into
security afterwards. Um and I guess
you know, maybe maybe even a precursor
to that question, what were the biggest
learnings that you had seeing the the
Kiro journey of what a good spec could
look like?
Yeah. Wow. Okay, that's a very loaded
question with a lot of
You can choose to you can
you can choose to answer those 10
questions that I just asked in any order
you wish.
Yeah. Yeah, I I think one
um
I I think I will first maybe go through
like what are what are some
uh some user experience things we tried
that ultimately didn't quite work out
because I think those are the intuitive
things that people jump towards, but
then it doesn't really quite click.
Um so, I think the the one example I'd
like to highlight is we tried um
basically aligning up specifications to
uh test to end-to-end test. Effectively,
every single spec just maps to an
end-to-end test. And if the test is
written, you can just run the code uh
run the vibe coding agent against those
tests until the test pass. So, that was
like a big initial stab at the problem.
And we thought, okay, you know, if
everything you say in the spec is true,
then there must be a test that matches
everything to be true.
But I think there's a practical problem
here, which is like we didn't quite
figure out how do you really synchronize
specification with code all the time,
right? Like map doing that one-to-one
mapping is kind of very hard because
language is unbounded, but then code has
very specific paths. And it could be
specifications that overlap, right? Like
one one one person might say, "Yeah,
this uh
this functionality should perform uh
user invite flows with admins only." And
another spec says, "No, it should only
provide user invite flows with uh
members only." And so, there's
conflicts, there's a lot of these
different problems, and especially hard
when you try to synchronize those
specifications with code
bidirectionally. So, I think what we've
learned very quickly on is like this
bidirectional thing, uh while it is an
aspirationally good idea, and I think
looks really cool on paper and on demos
and whatnot, it was actually not
practically implementable. And uh LLM
started to run much longer
in a way where the experience is not
feel enjoyable anymore. And, you know,
developers want to be in the flow,
right? So, it's my first my first like
intuitive thing that you that actually
turns out to not quite work is have
specifications map one-to-one to tests
and back and forth and keep keep all
these uh changes in sync. I think uh I
think that was a good learning about
like how do we now develop a
specification format approach that's
practical, right? Um and
and I think um before we go into what we
ended up doing in Kiro, I do want to
highlight uh a talk from Dex Horfee
around advanced context engineering for
coding AI agents. I'm not sure if you've
seen that before, but that's one of my
favorite talks. And he actually talks
through about how should coding agents
um manage their own context windows so
they can produce high-quality code at
the end, right? And
uh a key part that he talks about is
like you need to be you have the ability
for you to first do some research,
understand what is the end user outcome,
right? That you want to develop. And
then from there start creating a design
documentation almost like this is how
the system should be implemented, here
are the relevant factors that are
important. And then taking that design
artifact to ultimately create good
coding uh implementation plan and then
ultimately write the code for it. And
one thing he mentioned
that I that I think is highly relevant
is that if you have
um if you have one bad line
of
uh of a user story or a specification uh
in when you first research what you're
supposed to be doing, that will lead to
uh a thousand bad lines of a design.
And a thousand bad lines of design will
lead to, you know, a million bad lines
of code, right? So, really thinking
about how do you manage that context and
where to spend time is super important.
So,
how does that apply to a spec, right?
With specification, there's this meme
online where where there is like, "Next
time the execs ask me to build this
thing they just imagine, go build me
this site, no bugs, please. Go burr."
And and that's just not the reality,
right? The the most of the time is
thinking. And uh if you look at good
software engineering practices, they
don't just jump into the code directly.
The best engineers I've ever worked with
in my life, they're always are like
trying to understand, okay, what's the
end user outcome? What's the business
outcome we're trying to drive? What are
the constraints in the system?
And so, I would actually spend time to
really really think about what is the
user stories ultimately you want to
develop? What are the constraints that
you want to develop? And how what is
good enough now versus good enough for
the future? Like really lay that out.
And you can actually use, you know,
Claude, ChatGPT, kind of go work on work
on those things back and forth. And more
often than not, I realize it's really
good to ask Claude, "Hey, what am I
missing in the specification?"
And then you'll realize, "Oh, there are
some questions here that are super
relevant when I'm actually going down
implementation route that I forgot to
ask myself."
And when you when you develop that
approach where you really think about
the end outcomes, the constraints, and
then go and ask your your idea of
choice, be Kiro or something like Code
Layer, to go develop a design plan or
implementation plan, then the design
implementation plan are just better,
right? They're just more detailed,
they're more refined because just better
context management. And then from there,
the implementation of the code is just
better. Um and they're all more refined.
You can one-shot these 10,000-line PRs
that people can accept and because they
work, right? Um
And so, yeah, this is I think the most
important thing. Think about how to set
up your user stories, how to set up your
constraints, and keep asking someone
like Claude or ChatGPT for help see what
you're missing. Yeah, super interesting
cuz that I guess when I asked that
question, I wasn't I wasn't quite
specific in terms of, you know, what do
I mean the structure of a specification
or the layout of a specification? And
it's super interesting that you kind of
lean more into, you know, what is it
that a developer should put down. And I
think it's definitely a piece that is
overlooked. And I think you're
absolutely right whereby, well,
certainly when we think about the
difference between how a software
engineer would approach, you know,
something like a vibe coding exercise
versus here's a problem, let's start
writing some code. A developer would
absolutely stop and think before writing
the code, and they'd think about the
structure, etc. Whereas with vibe
coding, you're far more likely to
um just write something just to to to
short prompt and get something working
and then iterate. And I think it is very
interesting that actually this is a this
is a slightly different way of building
with LLMs. We do need to continue to to
step back and think about it and think
about the user and think about all those
all those types of considerations. So, I
love the I love the answer from that
point of view of uh
actually turning it into a craft of how
we build, which is the right way of
thinking about it. Yeah, and I think a
good like check for yourself is when you
realize that when you're in vibe coding
mode, the LLM will always tell you,
"Yes, you're absolutely right."
Yeah. Yeah. Whereas when you're thinking
about how to develop your spec, it will
actually ask you the hard questions that
you need to figure out, right? And you
want to be put into your position where
you're being asked the hard questions,
right? Where where there's the unknown.
And not just be like, "Oh, yeah, you're
absolutely right. Well, I'll I'll just
do exactly as you said." Right? It's
actually most of the times, even real
world, with anybody that you work with,
the people that only agree with you are
are not going to be the most productive
to you the ultimate outcome you're
trying to drive. You actually want
people to ask the hard questions so that
you can think through the details and
then really tease that apart so you can
deliver better product.
Yeah.
Yeah, fascinating. And I think I think
LLMs actually do a very very good job of
that, being able to, you know, question
your decisions or go deeper in things
that actually we may not even think
about because our focus our context
is is on it is is in a certain
perspective or a certain part of that
specification and we just actually admit
to think about those things and I think
LLMs possibly maybe even
you know, more than humans are very very
good at being able to ask those
questions that we wouldn't necessarily
naturally think about. Um what about
from a security point of view then cuz
obviously you're you're you're you're
you're leaning more and more into the
into the security field now. From a
security point of view, what do we need
to think about from a specification?
Yeah, I think um
let me maybe first start with my We're
going to jump into the second half of
our conversation, but first a quick
shout out to AI Native DevCon. Two days
of hands-on sessions, deep dives, and
honest conversations about what it means
to build AI native software. November
18th and 19th in New York or join
virtually from anywhere. Tickets and
details at ainativedev.io/devcon.
See you there. experience I've kind of
made with one of the first prototypes of
Kiro that I
This is like before I had an engineering
team, I built it myself
barely taped it together. So, this is
not the not the final product obviously
that that got shipped. But in this very
early prototype, I I basically developed
a specification around how should it go
and
how should this website look like I'm
building, where should it be hosted?
Obviously, I worked at AWS, it should be
hosted on AWS.
Um and then I basically just let it run
and I went for lunch. So, I left my
computer at work.
It was just like doing its thing. I'm
like, okay, now when I'm back, I'm sure
the website will be like it's fine,
right?
Um
When I came back, I was horrified cuz I
saw my terminal window literally blow up
with things and it was like a situation
where I realized, "Huh, yeah, it
actually never had access to my AWS
credentials.
The the deployment would have never gone
through.
But wait, there's a link. It's online.
What's going on, right?
So, it turns out it found a way.
Yeah, it it found a way. It found So, it
actually turns out it found some
hardcoded credentials that I
had on my computer from a development
environment that I had from long time
ago for a completely unrelated project.
It searched my entire file system using
a regex trying to match the AWS secret
access access token and secret key IDs.
And then it found those credentials,
piped that into the new project, and
deployed a new website. And I was just
like, "Oh my goodness. What is
happening?
Like, is this what AGI looks like?
Anyway, so
I was like, "Huh,
this is this is I mean, cool, but that's
also crazy. It's like very dangerous.
What's going on?" And luckily, it was
just my dev dev credentials, right, at
the time.
Um and that really compelled me to think
about, okay, what is the security aspect
as we go down this route when you know,
teams start shipping tens if not million
lines of code PRs every day um because
of this amazing technology that we have,
uh what are the security implications of
all of this, right? Mhm. And Mhm. I then
started researching and there's some
there's like this statistic about like
how LLMs have been generating code over
the last uh last few years and it went
somewhere from like 17% correct
syntactically correct to like 98%
correct last time we checked, which is
effectively almost 100%. Um And then I
was like, "Oh, that's cool. Like, it is
getting better at code. That's awesome."
But then if you look at the uh security
benchmarks, it's like flat and like just
very subtly going down even slightly.
And I'm just like wondering, "Oh wow, so
now we live in a world where we're
writing exponentially more code
while the security posture of them have
not improved and that basically creates
this Swiss cheese of a bunch of holes
all over our products all over this
surface area of the product and who's
going to go fix that? Who's going to go
find all those issues? It's so much
code, right? And so, that compelled me
to to start Cascade, right? To really
think about
how can we take a new refresh approach
on software security and try to figure
out what are the true vulnerabilities
that matter to you when you have
millions of lines of code shipping and
what are the ones that truly are
exploitable and what are the ones to
focus on, right? Um yeah, that's that's
that's a little bit of the the
background there.
Yeah, I'm curious. Did it Did it check
in your credentials to to a get repo
somewhere?
No, it did not. Actually, what it did is
it copied it and then prepended it into
the deployment command with CDK so that
I had the
So, so even worse, it was actually in my
bash history now. So, those those
credentials are saved.
It's It's one of those moments where you
don't know you almost can't be angry
because it's so impressive that it
actually found a path or a route to it,
right? And that's that's an interesting
thing like from a security point of
view, there there are so many different
ways an LLM can kind of
can kind of you know, come to a come to
an answer or or or find a resolution to
a particular a particular issue. It
seems it's almost like the WAF style of
you know, that there's if there's if you
imagine an infinite possibilities of
solutions, how can you how can you even
start thinking about
uh providing guidance or providing some
level of this is right, you can't do
this, this is wrong because I guess
those those rules will change based on
any number of different factors. Um I
guess why don't we talk why don't we
start talking a little bit about
um when is the best time to to to think
about security from an LLM's point of
view?
Uh
If we think about code, there are many
places where we can almost like
statically test where we where we can
ask the LLM to to to think about things
or review code from a from a security
point of view. Obviously, the offensive
testing is a little bit further further
right. Although I say further right, the
way LLMs are building and being able to
produce, it's not that far right. It's
only a it's only a tiny bit more
waiting, but you know, should we be
should we be looking at security all the
way through or is there a best place to
stop and then say, "Right, now we should
test and this is the best way of
testing." What are your thoughts on
that?
Yeah, I I think the software development
role is going through this massive
compression of skills.
Right? Like a parallel I would draw is
maybe uh 2 years ago asking a software
engineer to just build a UI without a
designer providing a Figma file or some
wireframe would be like, "Hey, it will
look so bad. It would be embarrassing to
ship it in front of the client."
But that's that's changed, right? So, I
think because people tend to be better
reviewers than they are creators. That's
like just the general human beings.
Like, you can always look at something
like, "Yeah, this this looks kind of
good or or bad." Like, you can judge it,
right? Um but creating it exactly as
somebody has painted it is very hard.
Right? So,
so I think we've already seen that
happen in different roles like obviously
design, certainly in product we see
great engineers who have like um product
acumen now be able to do more because
they have the time to do it. And I think
we'll see that with security as well
over time. Now, there are some
difficulties in security which is like
obviously, there's statically uh these
static analysis tools that everybody I
think should just have as like a
baseline. Most you know,
most integrations with GitHub kind of um
I there's many different integrations
with GitHub that come pre-installed out
of the box, right? So, should be a very
easy switch to flip if that makes sense.
Um
but with security,
it is not just purely a software
engineering problem or just purely a
security engineering problem. Uh
security cannot be looked in isolation.
It has to be looked at in the context of
the business.
Right? So, for example,
if you use a
a a a random scanner if you will, right?
For for like your
uh for your URLs that you expose on your
application,
it will flag that, "Hey, this particular
photo URL is public. You must have had
made a mistake."
But what if it's Google Photos and I
made that photo public by intention?
That is the business decision I have
made. And so, the lack of semantics in
security technologies today is causing
all of these false positives, noisy
alarms, and people are just swamped with
a bunch of different alerts and getting
paged without being actually
without without the tool actually being
aware of like, "Oh yeah, this actually
doesn't quite matter. It's really not
that important because this is what this
system was designed to do, right?" Um
and so, I think we'll see this
compression of security into software
engineering happen, but it will be a
little bit slower because there's even
more things that we need to kind of tie
together the business context, right? Um
obviously understanding security
paradigms, but also software engineering
paradigms.
And yeah, the the the thing I would
recommend for people developing uh with
specifications is also just have a
little like access control.env
file as part of your your stack
somewhere where you can just say, "Hey,
this is what I expect my end users to
do. Here are the different roles that
exist. This is what these roles are
supposed to do.
After you're done implementing, verify
against these different rules and see if
they were impacted or not and flag them
back to me or you know, re-implement the
change with those things in mind."
Something very simple as that
immediately adds so much semantic
context into the code that gets
generated so the LLM can help you be
better, right? It can help you develop
more secure software.
Mhm. I love that guidance to the agents.
I think that's that's definitely an area
that we're seeing certainly at Tessal
is is is such a key is such a key piece
to actually generating not just accurate
code but building the way an
organization or an individual wants to
wants to go about that that that
workflow.
If we go back to the very start of this
podcast, I kind of opened with with a
number of
you know super interesting quotes. One
of them
and I'll read this out so I don't get it
wrong. You hacked seven out of 16
publicly launched companies of the Y
Combinator spring batch in 30 minutes.
It took you 30 minutes. No, I'm joking.
30 minutes, seven out of 16. That's
that's that's amazing. Um first of all,
you like you know are these the kind of
applications that a vibe code is style
applications? Are they traditionally
built by developers in a you know in a
usual flow?
What what were the types that you that
you attacked there?
Yeah, yeah. I think um I think in our
batch over 95% of companies said that
they were using AI to help with their
coding. So
like at least if you want to know where
to start off sorry ad. If you're not
using AI, you're probably not going to
make it. Like this is
this is just where like a lot of
velocity comes from and it is really
impressive to see
um you go to demo see everybody that
you've started a batch with. Most of
them had $0 in ARR and then they get
hundreds of thousands of dollars in ARR
within such a short compression of time.
Used to be completely unheard of, right?
And seeing this amount of volume of
starters being able to accomplish that
should really really ingrain to
everybody that yep, using AI to code is
a competitive advantage you should
implement in your business, right? Now
imagine you're not just a couple of
people inside a startup but actually a
large organization, then you get these
compounding effects too.
Now, however
on the note of security, right?
One one aspect of it is I think in the
past, you know, a small team developing
software just could not build as quickly
as mission-critical of a software that
requires such attention to security.
Right? And that's just not true anymore.
Like you know, we had we had companies
in our budget had deals with the US
government by the end of it. Right? It's
like the security really really matters
here. Um or or like dealing with
financial institutions. And so suddenly
you have this
you know, small team of high-density
talent that's going to be able to create
extremely mission-critical software.
And that is where then security does
matter. So out of these 16 companies,
obviously they you know, it's no secret
everybody was using AI to build their
software but they were in different life
cycles of their stage. Could be like a
lot of the software has had been you
know, built over over a year already. Uh
but then they added a new feature
through just vibe coding and that
ultimately caused a new vulnerability in
your system. Right? There's also
obviously companies that just you know,
build
just completely airing hey LLM, please
build me this feature, please. Right?
Let's hope this works out kind of vibe
too. Of course, there's always this the
spread.
But I think what is super important is
with security, it's not like oh yeah,
80% of the
if 80% of the code has been handwritten
and security reviewed in the past, that
means I'm secure for the next year.
That's just not true in security.
Like if you just introduce a one
additional feature that is using
slightly different paradigm, it has
different access controls, different
configurations, that is an entirely new
vulnerability that's waiting to be
exploited potentially. Right? And so the
the reality is
the the best way to be able to security
test new software in the future as
they're so as the volume of software is
changing
getting exponentially more is to look at
it from offensive security standpoint.
Like we really try to hack your software
to the to the to the largest extent
possible so that we can find the
vulnerabilities that truly matter to you
that are truly exploitable. Um
and and I think we'll see that then
feedback into the software development
life cycle and self-improve the software
obviously by then patching the security
vulnerabilities as we go, right? Um
yeah, the the
the the situation right now is I think
just the very beginning of what we of
like the implications we see. Um imagine
once larger companies start adopting AI
even even even larger scale, right? Um
without without thinking about security
quite as much, then I think we'll start
to see some really really bad large
security breaches and in that moment I
think the entire industry will revisit
about how we implement security in this
age of you know, tens of thousands of
lines of PRs every day,
And would you say like a lot of these
you know
this this kind of like
prediction of a great number of breaches
and a great number of vulnerabilities um
for those larger organizations, should
they be
more worried about a new style of
vulnerability or a new a new attack
vector or is it really the same
vulnerabilities that we've always we've
come to know and love
that are just being scaled in terms of
the number that that exist in the code
base?
I mean look, the the answer is both,
right? Um like the
you'd be betting on the past if you
believe that code is going to get less.
That that is just not going to be true.
Like there's going to be exponentially
more code.
And with exponentially more code, you
will get more vulnerabilities that we
know of today. So that's I think
sticking around number one.
Sticking around number two is
software is going to become stochastic
instead of just deterministic.
Because we're because of our you know,
our use of LLMs throughout the entire
system, right? Be it to unlock an user
feature, be it to create that
reinforcement loop we talked about, be
it like for us to make some business
processes. Like your your software is
going to become stochastic. And through
stochastic software like you know,
working with LLMs, they have security
vulnerabilities. You can trigger them to
call a tool and that tool is maybe not
properly scoped and then suddenly you
can exfiltrate data.
Things like the lethal trifecta that Sam
Wilson likes to talk about a lot. It's
it is a new set of vulnerabilities as
well.
But I think what's even at least what's
for me even more important to think
about is that those things are now
coming in together. We have
exponentially more code and the behavior
of the code is less deterministic than
ever before.
And and so looking forward into that
into that future,
what what do you what do you think
developers need to change about the way
they work
or the way they think about security to
to better address this?
Mhm.
Yeah, I think I think first
the
being security-minded and having some
understanding of like good security
design is probably the most critical
piece because if you have thinking in
good design, you will get good code kind
of like you know, one good line of code
leads to 100 lines of good
implementation. One bad line of code
leads to 100 bad lines of
implementation. Right? So thinking about
security design, things like specifying
the access control matrix, uh
just writing down hey, this is what I
expect for rate limiting, right? Or
even if you don't know, ask Claude, what
is an industry accepted rate limit for
this type of an API? Right? Something
very basic like that can already just
throw that into your context you know,
into your context with LLM like a
markdown file can already help you a
lot, right?
And then the the other thing that I
think will happen is tools like Cascal
will proliferate, right? We will be
living a world where we want to make
software just effortlessly secure. So
that means you know, you committed some
code, it's in a preview branch, it's
immediately being security tested. You
can immediately find out why there is a
vulnerability in some way and that's
getting immediately fed into an LLM that
then can go and patch this code. You you
mentioned earlier as a joke,
what? It took you 30 minutes? Yeah, you
know, I I'm
And and and you know, I I think it was a
kind of kind of a joke that oh yeah,
that's actually kind of short short
amount of time. Uh I actually don't
think that's short enough of a time. My
mission is to make sure we can bring
that iteration time down so much it can
actually be naturally integrated as part
of your development life cycle. Now
obviously the cost of it as well so that
it's just part of your system.
In no other way we can we are able
without this, we would not be able to
make all software effortlessly secure.
So that that's really what I'm thinking
about every day. Yeah.
And that autonomy I think is always been
important generally in in in developer
workflows but because that's being sped
up now, because it's so so easy to
quickly build and create software
through a number of tools. That just
amplifies the need for for that
autonomy, right?
And I guess offensive security tooling.
Um
Is there any is there anything we need
to to change in terms of the way we
think about you know, more offensive
security testing versus the static
security testing and how we build those
into a typical workflow?
Yeah, yeah. Offensive security is a
interesting paradigm inside the software
development world, right?
Um
If you if you ask a lot of people that
you know, sell B2B software as part of
their compliance requirements, they will
perform a penetration test.
Uh and most compliance frameworks would
say one penetration test annually is
enough.
And still give you like, "Bam, you are
approved for this, you know, compliance
framework ABC."
I think that will have to change.
Because we're creating software at a
much faster rate.
Right? You can be secure on the day of
being pen tested, but the next day the
developer might have built a new feature
that you didn't know about or it was
like trying to experiment with
something. Whoops, suddenly the dev
credentials are in fraud, right? It's
like there's many things that are
changing at a rapid pace that we cannot
manage anymore. Right? So, once a year
penetration tests are not going to be
the future we're going to be living in.
And I think CISOs, especially on the on
the buyer side of software, need to
start insisting on more regular
penetration tests. Because like once a
year, like the By the time you've bought
the software, the software has already
changed by the time you've received it,
right? Um
So, so I think that is one one one piece
of like the the mindset around it that
that needs to needs to change. Um and
then second is I think we need to evolve
in a way where um
where the the penetration testing, the
offensive security, uh just gets
performed also at much shorter cycle
times and at much lower costs, right?
Like the reason why CISOs like companies
to buy penetration is because it is
considered the highest quality security
assessment that you could effectively
get. Right? But if it if it costs you
like $10,000 for like a serious one
that's not just like a random automated
scanner,
then it is cost prohibitive for most
companies in the world. And when when we
are building so much software,
$10,000 every time there's a software
change is just not going to work. So, we
need to be bringing down the cost on a
per penetration test basis dramatically
so that it's just part of your everyday
software development life life cycle.
You can maybe pay a small subscription
that's monthly, and it will just make
your security effortless because it will
just tell you, "Hey, yeah, we found a
new vulnerability and it's already
fixed. Here's a PR for that." Yeah.
It it it's amazing back my back in my
sneak days when I used to talk to a
whole bunch of uh different folks about
uh about when you know, as and when they
run different types of
uh security tests. And and when we talk
about the kind of pen testing style, the
number of people who said, "Oh, yeah, we
pen test." And I'm like, "Okay, how
often do you pen test?" "Oh, once every
6 months or once every, you know, year
or or major release." were the typical
answers I get. And it's like, "Right,
but you don't ship code once every 12
months, do you?" "No, no, no, we ship
code every week all the time." And it's
like, "Right, so so who's testing this
new code that you that you deliver?" And
there's no good answer. So, I think the
autonomy of that is is super critical.
Um what what if we flip the coin and
say, "Well, actually,
is the answer testing the code that the
AI
um
tools create, or is the solution getting
AI or or maybe hoping that AI will one
day deliver,
you know, more secure code, have fewer
vulnerabilities, get the models better
at generating code that is more
acceptable uh from a security point of
view? How do you see that future?"
Yeah, yeah.
So, I think the the LLMs should be
performing uh
code generation in a more secure manner.
I think there's a context problem that
we're working with today. Obviously like
putting this access control stuff into
your into your code base is important.
Right? There's there's just like
awareness of new security
vulnerabilities that are coming through
um that, you know, the LLM doesn't know
about yet because the they they were
discovered after the context cutoff
window from whatever the model was
trained. So, I think that's just like a
problem space on its own that will
exist.
However, I don't think we're going to be
able to
reach a world where that alone is
sufficient. Cuz if you ask any security
engineer, when they start looking at
your software and ask me a bunch of
security questions, the first thing they
do is draw a bunch of boxes on a diagram
and draw different arrows in between and
then start looking at, "Okay, what are
all these arrows doing?" Right? So, it's
always about how are things
interconnected and what is the business
semantics behind it. Right? And most of
those things are not necessarily just in
your code base or even in your own CI/CD
pipeline. You might be, you know,
calling an external service that
performs some work. And that external
service might change over time, too,
under under the hood without you
knowing, right? Um and so, there is a
range of different reasons for why your
at the time of building and releasing
you actually don't know the true
security posture of your software.
Right? And so, that is why I think
offensive security will evolve um
as a primary mechanism to assess
security posture of software moving
forward because we have solved the or
we're in the process of solving some of
the hardest problems in in this space
like automating, obviously, the pen
testing work, bringing in business
semantics, bringing in context,
continuously running it, lowering the
cost, making it run faster. These are
all things that are suddenly
capable because of generative AI. And
so, it will make what's already
considered in the past the best way to
assess your security posture actually
accessible to most companies in the
world, most software teams in the world.
And I think we can really live in a
world where all software is effortlessly
secure.
Yeah. And when that happens, and of
course I think the automation and the
continuous testing is is super key for
that. One thing that will
you know, very likely almost certainly
change is the roles that we as humans
play, not just in the development life
cycle in general, but um
thinking about it more from a security
engineering point of view.
Uh how do you see the role if uh
if this uh testing, pen testing,
offensive testing is is is more
autonomous, more part of the workflow,
what do we what do we expect security
engineers to to to focus on?
Mhm.
I I think in security engineering we'll
actually see
um a a similar wave, if you will, as we
had with software engineering. So, when
GitHub Copilot first came out um or and
then if ChatGPT wrappers and then the
first versions of like agentic IDEs came
out,
I mean, there was a lot of sentiment in
the in the world that
oh, you don't need as many software
engineers as before. Um the managers
could be able to do this work.
Right? But we all know now like that's
not the world we're living in. In fact,
high judgment, extremely good engineers
are we've just been significantly more
productive than ever before where we're
asking is middle management required,
right? So, I think the the the script is
actually flipping a little bit backwards
from even what the sentiment was like
two or three years ago when just these
things were coming out. And I think
we're feeling the same right now in
security, right?
I think the security issues are coming
out. They're like, "Oh, yeah, maybe we
don't need individual security
engineer." And like, that's not the
world that's that's not the reality of
the world that we're going to be in.
What will actually happen is the
security engineer can work on things
that they actually enjoy.
Um
Security engineers
spend more time
chasing down false positives today
than implementing fixes for security
issues.
That does not sound like a fun job.
Like could you imagine your entire day
is triaging warnings of things that you
have a pretty good hunch on that it's
not a real issue, but we're going to
spend 4 hours on each of these warnings
every day. That does not sound like a
fulfilling job. But you know what
excites security engineers? Actually
doing security research, teasing apart
individual bits of clues, and then
figuring out, "Oh, yeah, I can totally
exploit this system. I found another
vulnerability. Let me quickly go and fix
it." Like playing that detective role is
much more fun.
Or doing more strategic work, right?
Like thinking about how do I bring in
security into the platform engineering
space so it's consistent across the
organization. Those are actually things
people want to do. And I think we're
going to see that happen now with
security engineer where this this like
grunt work, all those painful things of
like alarms that didn't truly matter,
oh, this random header that you didn't
set that actually is not exploitable at
all. Like all of that work will finally
go away so that people can just live a
much more fulfilling life by working on
things they enjoy. And I think that is
just going to be an immense opportunity
for making sure that the security is
just baked into to your organizations
and people can just do things that are
um so much more that that that
ultimately create much more
effortlessness around security for the
rest of the organization.
Yeah, yeah. So, so Renee, we should we
should wrap up, but I'd love I'd love
one more take on on on one last one last
question. And I think when we think
about, you know, issues that have
occurred in in in the world, typically
we need a big hack or a big breach
before we start taking things seriously
and actually investing time and money
into these various risks. Um
given that there's so much change right
now, what what is the Let's try and
preempt that breach or that hack. What
would you say is like the biggest
security risk in software today
that the industry or companies are just
not taking seriously enough, not
investing the right time, money, and
effort into into trying to address?
I I will actually argue it is the the
biggest security risk is actually a
process risk.
Today we're in a situation where teams
are empowered, and rightfully so, to
deliver an unprecedented amount of
features and code in a very short time.
But we are not giving them the right
tools to make security just baked in and
effortless.
Like, today when when often times you
talk to organizations, security and
software engineering is just like, "Oh
my god, those are the guys that are
going to bring in all this bureaucracy,
make me do all this work, and you know,
half of those issues are false
positives." Like, that is actually a
process failure, right? And I think
everybody should reassess in their
organization. Do they have the right
process where security and engineering
are effectively swimming one lane
together and actually making sure that
both can deliver faster without stepping
on each other's toes. So, that means
bringing in more business context into
the security landscape, obviously,
giving them tools that make security
effortless, that doesn't give you all
these false positives don't really
matter, right? And also empowering
security engineers to be able to
contribute changes more directly into
into the actual software that's
shipping. Yeah.
Love it. Rene,
what a wonderful chat. Really, really
appreciate your time, and thank you for
so many insights, whether whether it be
spec security, uh various products,
defensive hacking. Really, really
interesting conversation. Thank you so,
so much for joining us today.
Yeah, thanks for having me. And yeah, if
you want to learn more about autonomous
security testing, go to casco.com, c a s
c o.com. Wonderful. Thank you very, very
much. And for our podcast listeners,
thank you. I hope you enjoyed that
episode. Uh tune in to the next session.